Register of the Julius Epstein Papers, 1939-1975
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE. (Boxes 1-86.)
  - Polish-German boundary (official U.S. position)
  - Polish Government
  - Polish leaders missing
  - Political failure in Germany
  - Ponger, Kurt L. and Verber, Otto
  - Pope, Arthur Upham
  - Population (Box 52)
    - Information
    - Reference Bureau
  - Portugal (J. E.)
  - Portuguese counterfeit story (J. E.)
  - Posadovsky
  - Possev
  - Possony, Stefan, 2 folders)
  - Post-war governments in exile
  - Post-war Soviet Russia
  - Postal matter
  - Potsdam
    - Conference
    - Papers
  - Pound, Ezra
  - Pravda
  - 'Predictions'
  - Prehistory of World War III (begun December 16, 1944)
  - Presidential veto
  - Press
    - Of New York City
    - Release list
    - Wireless
  - Preventive war
  - 'Prince' Romanov
  - Psychological War Board, 1953
  - Psychological warfare leaflets
  - Public flogging
  - Public Law 726 (advances the cause of freedom)
  - Publications - Announcements
  - Pucheu, Pierre
  - Puerto Ricans in New York
  - Puerto Rico
  - Pulitzer Prize, 1947
  - Pumpkin Papers, 2 folders)
  - Pushbutton trend
  - Pushkin's grave
  - Pusta, Kaarel, 2 folders)
  - Putlitz, Wolfgang
  - Puttkamer, Jesco von, "Irrtum und Schuld", 2 folders)
  - Quotations
  - Rackets
  - Radescu, Nicolae
  - Radiation fallout (Nevada)
  - Radio
  - Radio Free Europe
    - General
    - Broadcasts
    - Criminal blunders
    - Critical voices
    - White wash
  - Radio 'Liberty'
    - General
    - Releases
  - Raeder, Erich (Box 53)
  - Rankin vs. Deutsch
  - Rapallo
  - Rauschning, Hermann
    - General
    - Publicity
      - English, American
      - German
  - Rauschning, Mrs. - Research
  - Reader's Digest, 2 folders)
  - Red Army, The myth of the
  - Red China recognition
  - Rediess, Wilhelm (Nazi general)
  - Refugee Defense Committee
  - Refugee Relief Act, 1953
  - Reichenau, Walter von
  - Reilly, Michael F. (F.D.R.'s bodyguard)
  - Remer, Otto Ernst
  - Reporter on American Soviet Relations
  - Reprint release number 1
    - Letter
    - List
  - Republican Convention
    - 1944
    - 1964
  - Republican Party
  - Republican platform, 1964
  - Republican record since 1932
  - Research institutions
  - Reston, James
  - Reuter Dinner
  - Reves, Emery
  - Review of World Affairs
  - Reynaud, Paul
  - Rhee, Syngman
    - General
    - March 1954
  - Richter, Eugen
  - Rickenbacker, Eddie
  - Ridder, Viktor F.
  - Riedel, Walther
  - Rieger, Elsa
  - Riess, Kurt
  - Riesser - Memorandum (on prisoners of war)
  - Riom trials
  - Ripka, Hubert
  - Roberts, Owen J.
    - General
    - Commission
  - Robot bomb
  - Rockets
  - Rockwell, Norman
  - Roda Roda
  - Roetgen (Germany) (Box 54)
  - Rogge, John O.
    - General
    - "My New Plan for Peace"
  - Rohrer, Charles C.
  - Rommel, Erwin
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (concerning her husband)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano
    - Correspondence with Ibn Saud
    - Gunther's story
    - His men
    - Plagiat accusation, Pegler
    - Speeches
      - General
      - To American Youth Congress
      - Four Freedoms
    - Writings (selections)
  - Roosevelt, F. D., Jr.
  - Ropke, Wilhelm
  - Rosenberg, Alfred
  - Ross, Irvin and Hicks, Granville (on communism)
  - Rothkirch, Eduard von
  - Rougier, Louis
  - Round Table
  - Rowan, Carl
  - Royal Yugoslav Information Center
  - Royal Norwegian Information Services
  - Ruby, Jack
  - Ruhr
    - Area
    - Administration
    - Agreement, December 1948
  - Rules Committee
  - Rundstedt, Gert von
  - Russell, Bertrand, Lord, 3 folders)
  - Russell, Francis J.
  - Russian broadcasts of the State Department
  - Russian 'free' press
  - Russian language guide
  - Russian Orthodox Church
  - Russian-Polish dispute
  - Russian-Polish 'friendship'
  - Russian slave labor on German soil (New Leader article)
  - Russian State Party Newsletter on Contemporary Communism, The
  - Russians in 'liberated' countries
  - Russo-German relations
  - Rutz, Henry
  - Rybakoff, Nicholas P.
  - "Die Saat des Verrats"
  - Salazar, Antonio de Oliveira
  - Sales, Raoul de Roussy de, Count, 2 folders)
  - Salisbury, Harrison E.
  - Salter, Andrew
  - San Francisco (Box 55)
    - Charter
    - Conference
  - SANE (California Council)
  - Sassoon, Victor
  - Satellite peace treaties
  - Saturday Evening Post (editorials)
  - Sauckel's family
  - Saxony's castles destroyed
  - Scarbeck, Irvin C.
  - Schacht, Hjalmar, 2 folders)
  - Schlamm, William C., 2 folders)
  - 'Schlechte Schuler'
  - Schleicher, Kurt von
  - Schlozer, Kurd von
  - Schmidt, Guido
    - General
    - Trial
  - Schmidt, Paul
  - Schoerner, Ferdinand
  - Scholl, Sophie and Hans
  - Schoolbooks
  - Schulenburg, Count (Washington correspondent)
  - Schultz, Benjamin
  - Schuman, Frederick L.
  - Schuschnigg, Kurt
  - Schwarz, Salomon
  - Schwarzenbach
    - Exposes
    - Translation
  - Schwarzschild, Leopold
  - Schwimmer, Rosika
  - "The Science of Making Sense"
  - Scoop
  - Scorza, Carlo
  - Secret agreements' repudiation
  - "Secret Covenant, Secretly Arrived at" (J. E. - Material)
  - Secretaries of State
  - 'Security' in Washington
  - Sedition trial
  - Seeckt, General von - Papers (Box 56)
    - Miscellaneous
    - The partition of Poland - Memorandum, 1916
    - Letter to Groner, May 6, 1919
    - The rearmament of Germany for defense against Bolshevists - Memorandum, February 26, 1920
    - The military and political situation in the East - Memorandum July 31, 1920
    - Germany and Russia - Memorandum, 1920
    - Baltics - Memorandum, 1920
    - "Promemoria-Ostpolitik" - Brockdorf-Rantzau's Memorandum, July 15, 1922
    - Germany's position toward the Russian problem - Memorandum in answer to the preceding document, September 11, 1922
    - Von Reischach to Seeckt, October 16, 1926
    - Letter to Kahr, November 5, 1928
    - The army of the Soviet Union - Memorandum, December 16, 1932
    - Memorandum to Chian Kai-shek, June 30, 1933
    - On Bismarck, 1936
    - Tschunke's Memorandum, February 13, 1939
    - Quotations from Groner's memoirs
    - "Die Seeckt Dokumente" (J. E.; German and English versions)
    - Seeckt's memorandum of September 11, 1922 (published in the Washington Post on February 22, 1948)
    - J. E.'s article on the Seeckt papers in the Standard-Times, May 20, 1948
  - Seger, Gerhart
  - "Selbstbestimmung und Volkerrecht" by Leo Pfeil
  - Seldes, George
  - Serbs
  - Serge, Victor
    - General
    - "Inside the Comintern"
  - Sergeev, Sergei M. (Box 57)
  - Sergio, Lisa
  - Service, John Stewart, 3 folders)
  - Seversky, Alexander de
    - On atomic war
    - "Bomb the Axis from America," 1943
    - "Our antiquated defense policy," 1949
  - Shaw, George Bernard, 2 folders)
  - Sheen, Fulton J., Monsignor, 2 folders)
  - Sherrod, Robert, "The Inside Story of the Korean Truce"
  - Shipkov, Michael T.
    - General
    - New York Times story, March 5, 1950
  - Shirer, William L., 2 folders)
  - Short, Irving
  - Shuster, George N., 3 folders)
  - Siberian bases
  - "Sie wissen, dass sie verloren sind" ("They Knew They Were Lost: The German Elite Had no Faith in Victory," by J. E.)
  - Siebenburgisch, American newspaper, Cleveland, Ohio
  - Sikorski, Wladyslaw
  - Silesian priests
  - Simms, Philip
  - Sinatra, Frank
  - Sinclair, Upton
  - Singer, Kurt
  - Sky Tower
  - Smith, Bedell
    - On liberation of Poland
    - On Red China and the UN
  - Smyth report on atomic energy
  - Snow, Edgar, 2 folders)
  - Social security
  - Socialist International
  - Society for the Prevention of World War III
  - Society for the Prevention of World War III, 4 folders) (Box 58)
  - Socony-Vacuum Company
  - SOFAR (Sound Fixing and Ranging)
  - Soil erosion in the U.S.
  - Sokolsky, George E.
    - General
    - List
  - Solf, Hanna
  - Sollmann, William F.
  - Sontag, Raymond
  - Soustelle, Jacques
  - South America
  - South Germany and Austria (statistics)
  - South Tyrol
  - Souvarine, Boris
  - Soviet admissions
  - Soviet ambassadors
  - Soviet anthem
  - soviet Armenians
  - Soviet Autonomy Decree
  - Soviet concentration camps
  - Soviet decrees
    - 1917
    - And laws, 1917-1919
  - Soviet disarmament
  - Soviet documents
  - Soviet foreign policy (Box 59)
    - Treaties
    - U.S. official publication
  - Soviet Gestapo in Soviet Zone
  - Soviet gold, 3 folders)
  - Soviet Government's recognition by others
  - Soviet guided missiles
  - Soviet imperialism - Maps
  - Soviet lead in atom smashers
  - Soviet living standard
  - Soviet moon shot
  - Soviet oil
  - Soviet-Polilsh situation after World War I
  - Soviet portraits (Bolshevist)
  - Soviet power in 1970
  - Soviet production
  - Soviet Republics (the sixteen Soviet Republics), 2 folders)
  - Soviet Russia Today, 2 folders)
  - Soviet Russian Communist Party, 1917-1919
  - Soviet sailor
  - Soviet scientists
  - Soviet statistics
  - Soviet supply protocols
  - Soviet Ukraine
  - Soviet Union
    - 1937
    - And disarmament
    - Life in
  - Soviet views on war, non-aggression and peace
  - Soviet Zone constitution and electoral law
  - Sozialdemokraten Landeskonferenz
  - Space science
  - Spain (Box 60)
    - General, 4 folders)
    - Civil War
    - And the Axis
    - As future ally
    - Sources
  - "Spanish Foreign Policy (1898-1960)"
  - Spandau prison
  - S.P.D. underground
  - Spellman, Cardinal
  - Spengler, Oswald
  - Spiegel (Spiegel affair)
  - Spiegel, Baron von
  - Spitsbergen
  - Spy-catching
  - St. Pierre et Miquelon
  - Stahmer, Heinrich
  - Stalin, Joseph
    - General
    - Achieved socialism, purges...
    - In Afghanistan
    - In Africa, 2 folders)
    - Against aggressions of others
    - Against help to Russia
    - Agents
      - In Germany
      - In the U.S.
    - Aid to Hitler (1933-1939 period)
    - In Alaska
    - Allurement with the lost provinces
    - In the Antarctics
    - Answers to Hugh Baillie
    - Anti-American propaganda in Russia
    - In Argentina
    - In Asia
      - General
      - Policy in Asia
    - Atheism
    - 'Atlantic Charter'
    - Atom bomb
      - General
      - Canadian spy case
      - Germany
      - Article material
    - Atom espionage
    - Atrocity in Korea
    - In Austria
      - General
      - Violated treaties
    - In the Balkans
      - General
      - Bulgaria, 2 folders)
      - Disposes of the Balkans
      - New Leader supplement
    - In the Baltics
      - General
      - The Baltic Review
      - Estonia, 2 folders) (Box 61)
      - Finland
      - Latvia
      - Lithuania, 3 folders)
    - And Benes
      - General
      - Secret treaties, 4 folders)
    - And Bidault, 2 folders)
    - In Brazil
    - Break with
    - Broken pledges
    - Broken treaties
      - General, 2 folders)
      - 1953
      - Consequences which should be drawn
      - New material, October 1950
      - Simms' articles, 2 folders)
      - State Department
        - List of May 29, 1948
        - White Paper, 1948
      - Teheran, Yalta, Potsdam
    - 'His' Bucar, Annabelle (Box 62)
    - In Bulgaria
      - Split of Communist party
      - U.S. Embassy conflicts
    - Byzantinism
    - Canal system
    - Censorship
    - In Central America
    - Chart
      - General
      - Material, 2 folders)
    - In China
      - General, 2 folders)
      - Bolton Report, "The Strategic and Tactics of World Communism"
      - Bouscaren's article
    - Churches
    - Cominform - Germans
    - And the coming war
    - Comintern puppets
    - 'Communism in 1960'
    - Concentration camps, 3 folders)
    - Courts
    - "Cultural and Scientific Exchange with the U.S."
    - In Czechoslovakia
    - Defense budget, 1948
    - Denazification, 2 folders)
    - Deportations
      - General, 2 folders)
      - 1951
    - 'Dismembers' Germany
    - Dream
    - In East Prussia
    - Economic crises
    - Economy, as shown for 1937
    - Election speech of February 9, 1946
    - Europe, Penetration in
    - Finland, threatened
    - Finnish-Soviet pact, 2 folders)
    - Forces the Western Powers
    - Foreign policy since World War I
    - In France
    - 'Freedom of the press'
    - Front (and fellow-travelers) organizations in the U.S.
    - Genocide, 3 folders)
    - Germ warfare
      - General, 2 folders)
      - Accusations
    - German agents
    - German atom-diggers
    - German economy
    - German industry
    - German lure
    - German 'proposal,' March 1952
    - German reparations
    - German uranium mines
    - In Germany
    - 'Gifts'
    - Gold
    - H-bomb
    - In 'history' books
    - Howard interview
    - In Hungary
      - General, 4 folders)
      - Nagy series
      - Neal Stanford's article
    - Hydroelectric power
    - Imperialism
      - General, 3 folders)
      - Imperial Communism (Wilcox pamphlet) (Box 63)
      - Map with figures
      - Carrefour map
      - Official State Department data
    - Industry, 1947
    - Interviews
      - General
      - New York Times, 1952
      - Pravda, 1951
    - On inventions
    - In Iran
    - In Iraq
    - In Italy, 2 folders)
    - In Japan
    - And Jews
    - Katyn crime
      - J. E.'s article, 2 folders)
      - J. E.'s letter to the London Times
      - German version, 2 folders)
    - His Katyn for the Germans
    - Kingsbury Smith's interview
    - In Korea, 3 folders)
    - Labor laws in Germany
    - In-law (his second wife's sister)
    - Lend-lease
    - Lenin Academy
    - Lie, Trygve
    - Lifestory, by Louis Fischer
    - 'Literature'
    - In Manchuria
      - General, 2 folders)
      - "Manchurian Manifesto"
    - Marriage laws
    - Massel
    - In Middle East
    - Militarism
    - Military academies
    - Military budget, 1949
    - Military forces in Germany
    - Military weakness
    - New Comintern
      - General
      - Articles in the New Leader, one by J. E., 2 folders)
    - New German army
      - General
      - Articles in Samedi Soir
      - Continental News Service
      - Foreign clippings
      - Foreign press
      - J. E.'s letter to the Washington Post
      - J. E.'s letter to the New York Times, 2 folders)
      - MacGowan's article
      - Schweizer Illustrierte Zeitung
      - U.S. press
    - New line, October 1952 (Box 64)
    - New party organization
    - N.K.V.D. (M.V.D.)
    - Non-German prisoners
    - In Norway
    - Not-to-talk order
    - Offenses
    - Omissions
    - In Palestine, 3 folders)
    - In Panama
    - Panslavism
    - Von Paulus
      - Denial of extradiction
      - Government
    - In Paris
      - Spring 1949
      - At World 'Peace' Conference, 1949
    - Peace offensive, 1949, 2 folders)
    - Poem in Pravda
    - In Poland, 4 folders)
    - Polit Bureau
      - General
      - Operational code
    - Post-war international relations
    - Post-war party line
    - Post-war treaties
    - Pravda, interview of October 28, 1948
    - Price reduction
    - Prisoners of war
      - General, 3 folders)
      - 1952
      - Camps
    - Prizes, 1948
    - Pro-Hitler attitude (additional material)
    - Promises of November 6, 1941
    - In Puerto Rico (assassination plot)
    - Puppets, 3 folders)
    - Radio, 2 folders)
    - Real wages
    - Recognised in 1933
    - Religious policy
    - Renegates
    - "Rogues Gallery," by George Creel
    - In Romania (Camil Ring series)
    - Roosevelt, Quarrel with
    - Russia's potential power (Life article)
    - Russian army
    - Sabotage plan
    - In Scandinavia
    - Schoolbooks
    - Scoffs at Allied war aid
    - Secret agreements with Hitler
      - General
      - Daily Telegraph
      - Pact
      - Sokolsky, George
    - Secret treaties with Hitler
      - General
      - Bevin confirms, 2 folders) (Box 65)
      - First offical publication by General Clay
      - Halder memoirs
      - House of Commons debates
      - Labor Action
      - Manchester Guardian
      - Marshall's declaration
      - Neue Volkszeitung
      - New Leader (second edition)
      - New York Journal American
      - New York Times
      - Newsweek
      - Official State Department publication, "Nazi-Soviet Relations 1939-1941", 4 folders)
      - Stalin's reaction to State Department publication (Box 66)
      - Stalin's complete official answer, 2 folders)
      - Stanford's article
      - Stokes' article
      - U.S. press comment to State Department publication
      - Vishinsky interview
    - Secret treaty with Mao
    - Self-criticism
    - Separate peace, 3 folders)
    - Shifts in government
    - Sickness
    - In Sinkiang
    - Slave labor camps
      - General, 2 folders)
      - "Russia's New Serfdom," by W. H. Chamberlin
      - Foreign clippings
      - On German soil
    - "From Socialism to Communism"
    - Son Vassily
      - General, 2 folders)
      - Hoax
      - In labor camp
    - In South America, 5 folders)
    - Sovereignty (Professor E. Korovin)
    - Soviet government
    - In Spain
      - General
      - Civil War, 1936-1939
      - 1950
    - Spies
      - General, 2 folders)
      - In the U.S.
        - Edna Logan's article
        - Look article
    - In Spitzbergen
    - Stassen interview
    - Tambow (camp for French prisoners)
    - Tannu-Tuwa
    - Teheran pledges
    - Third world war (military aspects as seen by communists)
    - Thirty years of
    - Thorez line
    - In Tibet
    - Tito, Dispute with
      - General
      - Ruth Fischer's article
    - Tomato
    - Treason blueprint
    - In Trieste, 3 folders)
    - Troops in Europe
    - In Turkey
      - General
      - "The Dardanelles Drama," by E. Bisbee
      - National Zeitung
      - "Stalin's Twarted Turkish War" (J. E.'s article)
      - Washington Post's article by J. E.
    - Unbroken treaties (material)
    - UNRRA
    - Uranium mines in Germany, 2 folders)
    - The U.S. as he views it
    - U.S. Negroes
    - And the Vatican
    - Veto
    - Victory over Japan
    - 'Victory speech,' 1954
    - Wage policy
    - At the Waldorf (Box 67)
      - General, 2 folders)
      - List of sponsors and program
      - New York Times, March 24, 1949
      - Sponsors
    - Wants war (Voznesensky's book)
    - On war
    - War guilt (J. E.'s letter to the New York Times, February 13, 1947)
    - In Western Europe (loss of membership)
    - Wick interview
    - Workers' standard of living
    - World strength (communist parties' membership figures)
    - Worse than Hitler
    - Writings - Earlier books, 4 folders)
    - Zhebrak purged
    - Zhukov
  - Stalin, Vassily, General. See Stalin, Joseph/Son Vassily
  - Stalinism in action ("Communism in Action," Representative Dirksen's study)
  - Stampfer, Friedrich, 2 folders)
  - Starr, Virginia
  - Stassen, Harold E.
    - General
    - Hearings before McCarren Committee
    - Letter to Stalin, October 4, 1950
  - State Liquor Authority (SLA)
  - Steel, Johannes
    - General, 4 folders)
    - Report
  - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur, 2 folders)
  - Steinhardt, Laurence A.
  - Steinhausen, Hermann von
  - Stelling, Johannes
  - Stepinatz, Archbishop Aloysius - Interview
  - Sternberg, Fritz
  - Stettinius, Edward R., Jr.
  - Steuben glass
  - Stevenson, Adlai (Box 68)
    - Cuba crisis
    - Interview, February 24, 1963
    - Statement in the Security Council on Congo
    - Statement on the UN
  - Stewart hearing on Katyn Forest Massacre
  - Stilwell, Joseph W.
  - Stokes, Richard L., "United States vs. Russia", 2 folders)
  - Stokes, Thomas L.
  - Stone, Shepard
  - Stone, William T.
  - Stork Club
  - Stout, Rex
  - Strachey, John (British Minister of War)
  - Strasser, Otto, 2 folders)
  - Strategic bombing
  - Strategic goods, Sale of
  - Streit, Clarence K.
  - Stringersoll, Alf
  - Strong, Anna Louise
  - Sturzo, Luigi
  - "Submission to Moscow," by Robert Muhlen
  - Subversive organizations, 2 folders)
  - Sudeten-Germany White Book
  - Sudeten Memorandum
  - Sudetenland (Anschluss)
  - Suez Canal
  - Suhl, Heinrich Ludwig
  - Sukarno
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays, 2 folders)
  - Sulzberger, C. L.
  - Sun Yat-sen, Madam
  - Supreme Court decision (school segregation)
  - Surrender documents
  - Swedish neutrality
  - Swing, Raymond G.
  - Swiss aid to refugees
  - Switzerland
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Army
    - History
  - Sychrava, Lev
  - Symans, Edward A.
  - Syllabication
  - Szilard, Leo (New York Herald Tribune interview, April 1960)
  - Taft, Robert A.
    - Death
    - Heckscher's articles
    - Speech, January 5, 1951
    - Statement, September 12, 1952
  - Tassigny, Jean de Lattre de
  - Tassoyev, J. D., Colonel
  - Taylor, Henry J.
  - Teheran (Box 69)
    - Conference
    - Papers
  - "Tell the West"
  - Ten Colonels
  - Test Ban Treaty
  - Tetens, T. H., "Know your Enemy"
  - Thailand
  - Thames & Hudson (promotion st.)
  - "They Knew They Were lost: The German Elite Had no Faith in Victory" (J. E.)
  - Thomas, Norman
  - Thomas, Parnell J.
  - Thompson, Dorothy
    - General
    - Article about Budzislawski
  - Thorez, Maurice
  - Thule
  - Thyssen, Fritz
  - Tillich Committee
  - Time issues, 2 folders)
  - The Times, London, air edition, 2 folders)
  - Thalmann, Ernst
  - Tito, Marshal
    - General, 4 folders)
    - Interviews, 2 folders)
    - UN speech, 1963
    - Vs. Stalin
  - Titoism
    - In China
    - In Italy
  - Todt, Fritz
  - Togliatti, Palmiro
  - Tokaev, Grigori A., 2 folders)
  - Toledano Column
  - Tompkins Column (New York Journal American, December 8, 1952) on Katyn Forest Massacre
  - Torberg, Friedrich
  - Torgler, Ernst
  - Tory leaders (Box 70)
  - "Toward Peace" (documents)
  - Town Meeting of the Air
  - Toynbee, Arnold J.
  - Trade Agreement, Geneva, October 30, 1947 (analysis of GATT)
  - Trans-Jordan
  - Translators
  - Trappists
  - Travell, Janet, Dr.
  - Treasury proposal
  - Treaties, Bibliograph on the Law of
  - Treviranus, Gottfried R.
  - Tribalism. See cannibalism
  - Die Tribune
  - "The Triumph of the Church"
  - Trivanovitch, Vaso
  - Trotsky, Leon
  - Trotsky, Natalie
  - Trotskyites in the U.S.
  - Troy Freie Presse
  - Troyanovsky, Alexander A.
  - Truman, Harry S
    - Arnold's speech
    - On the Baltics
    - Blunders - Foreign policy
    - Committee
    - On communism (speech, February 22, 1950)
    - Election, 1948
    - Election, 1948 (Box 71)
    - Firings
    - Inauguration, 1949
    - Letters
      - To the Daily Worker
      - To Ibn Saud
    - And McCarthy (Truman held that stalinism is not communism)
    - No-third term 'promise'
    - Opens up
    - On red lies
    - Speeches
      - General
      - 1947
    - State of the Union Message, 1949
    - Steel seizure
  - Trusteeship Council (missions)
  - Tunisia and Morocco
  - Turkey
  - Twain, Mark (copyright case)
  - Tygodnik Ilustrowany
  - Ukraine. See also Soviet Ukraine
  - The Ukrainian Quarterly
  - Unions
  - United Nations
    - General
    - Food Conference, 1943
  - United Nations Organization (Box 72)
    - Accomplishments
    - American Committee (on U.S. policy toward the UN)
    - Atomic energy
      - General
      - Commission
        - General, 2 folders)
        - First Report to the Security Council
    - Blocks
    - Cara-Pen (International Union for Cultural Cooperation)
    - Charter of the United Nations, Rules of the Security Council, and Statute of the International Court of Justice
    - Communists and fellow travelers
    - Declaration on the Right of Asylum
    - Delegates guide
    - Department of Economic Affairs
    - Double standard
    - Economic and Social Council, 3rd session (ECOSOC)
    - Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO)
      - General
      - Pamphlets
    - General Assembly
      - London, January-February 1946
        - General
        - Resolutions
      - New York, October 1946
        - General, 2 folders)
        - General (Box 73)
        - Budget, 2 folders)
        - List of delegates
        - Rules of procedure
        - Telephone directory
      - New York, 1947